

[(+44) 07483399901 | ■ liamganose@gmail.com | ☐ liamganose | ☐ liamganose

About Me

I am a dedicated site reliability engineer with a background in a tech-driven systematic hedge fund. My expertise lies in the development and operation of live trading systems, and process automation to enhance reliability and reduce the potential for human error. I've extensively developed monitoring and alerting mechanisms within Kubernetes environments and consistently offer responsive first-line production support. With over 5 years of professional experience in software engineering and infrastructure automation, complemented by a strong proficiency in Python, my passion for technology drives me. I am keen to further my journey as an engineer, particularly within the finance and technology sectors.

Skills_

Programming Python · JavaScript · Go · Bash

DevOps Docker · Kubernetes · Jenkins · Airflow · Git · Linux · Bazel

Web DevFlask · TypeScript · React · FastAPI · RESTAnalyticsSQL · Excel/VBA · PySpark · Pandas · SKLearn

Work Experience ___

The Voleon Group

London, UK

SITE RELIABILITY ENGINEER - PRODUCTION OPERATIONS TEAM

Jul. 2021 - Present

- Led and mentored a 5-person team; directly assisting with technical challenges and managing their workload.
- Mentored and trained over 15 new employees on in-house/open-source tooling.
- Built a custom SLA and monitoring system on Kubernetes which paged on-call staff for pipeline delays and infrastructure outages.
 - This has caught hundreds of potential issues from becoming severe incidents.
- Improved fixed income data mapping code which increased simulated PnL by over 2%.
- Migrated multiple research and production pipelines to a new file system in a different data centre with 100% uptime.
- · Development, improvement and maintenance of a trading system (Python) being orchestrated by Airflow DAGs.
- Involved in first line support debugging production issues which would be critical to the trading day if not remediated.
- · Worked on a production critical system where developing efficient, scalable and maintainable code is extremely important.
 - This involved working with DevOps tooling; such as Kubernetes, Jenkins (CI/CD) and Prometheus.

PwC London, UK

SENIOR ASSOCIATE - TECHNOLOGY, DATA & ANALYTICS TEAM

Sep. 2018 - Jul. 2021

Worked on many projects in different technical areas; such as full-stack web development, machine learning, process automation and big data. All of this work was in the finance industry. Examples include:

REGULATORY REPORTING TOOL

Tier 1 Investment Bank

- · Designed and built a highly automated cloud-based tool which ran a series of analytical regulatory reporting tests.
- Presented results in an interactive D3.js dashboard.
- This reduced the current auditing process from 3+ people working manually for multiple days down to 30 seconds.

AUDIT AUTOMATION TOOL Internal

- · Setup CI/CD infrastructure on Azure to automate the testing of machine learning models before publishing to production.
- Built a web application using a Flask back-end and a React front-end connected via REST APIs.
- Designed and built a React dashboard to show the results of each test, including comparisons to previous runs.
- This massively reduced manual testing time and increased the overall quality of the models.

ANTI-MONEY LAUNDERING INVESTIGATION

International Retail Bank

- Helped build a screening algorithm using PySpark on a Hadoop ecosystem to identify suspicious payments.
- Trained and deployed a machine learning model to identify True/False positives from the results of the screening algorithm.
- This reduced the manual review time of these results from months to minutes.
- Wrote reports and documentation on the code which were presented to legal counsel and then used in legal proceedings.

Education

University of Lancaster

Lancaster · UK

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND MATHEMATICS

Sep. 2015 - Jul. 2018

• Relevant Comp-Sci Modules: Software Development · Databases · Artificial Intelligence · Languages and Compilation · Security and Risk

• Relevant Maths Modules: Linear Algebra · Probability Theory · Stochastic Processes · Bayesian Inference · Financial Mathematics